有个混球从我衣柜里跌出来说要找我爸
Some asshat pops out of my closet asking about my dad.
亨利・温彻斯特
Henry Winchester.
伙计  那是我们爷爷
Dude, that's our grandfather.
我父亲和他的先辈都是记录者
My father and his father before him were both men of letters.
约翰和你们俩也该是的
As John and you two should have been.
我们的父亲教我们怎么猎魔
Our father taught us how to be hunters.
-好吧  那是什么  -我也不知道
- Okay, what's that? - I wish I knew.
我开始觉得我没能活着回去  是吗
I'm beginning to gather I don't make it back from this time, do I?
盒子里有一把钥匙能找到一切
In the box is the key to every object,
卷轴  咒语  几千年来收集的所有东西
scroll, spell ever collected for thousands of years
都放在一个地方
under one roof.
把钥匙带到这个地点
Take it to these coordinates.
那地方还存在的可能性有多大
What are the chances that place is still standing?
我想  我们总得试一试
A chance we've got to take, I guess.
白俄罗斯  维台普斯克
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
你来晚了
别怪我  怪鞋匠的女儿吧
幸运的混蛋
得淋病吧
那东西打不倒
已经冲破东门的防线了
长官  它把理查撕成了两半
天呐  到底是什么东西
它是来杀你们的
准备好武器吧
所有人  不是他死  就是你们亡
诅咒你  艾伯拉罕的巫师
隐身烟幕  我点燃你
火诞于血
不留任何人
将我融入夜色吧
力量和隐蔽的火焰
告诉你主子这事没完
凶鬼恶灵
第八季 第十二集
堪萨斯  黎巴嫩
这儿多久没来过人了
When's the last time somebody was in this place?
65  70年了吧
65, 70 years ago.
人人都恨希特勒
天呐
Son of a bitch.
瞧啊
Look at this.
业余无线电  电报机  总机
Ham radio, telegraph, switchboard.
这是他们的指挥中心
This was their nerve center.
亨利提到有一队听命于听命的猎人
Henry did say that they ran dispatch on their own team of hunters.
咖啡没喝完  棋也没下完
Halfway through their coffee and a game of chess --
看来原来驻守这里的人离开时很匆忙
Looks like whoever was manning the hub left quick.
一个警戒信号让记录者四散而逃
On the alarm call that ended the men of letters.
我去啊
Son of a bitch.
小萨姆  我们找到蝙蝠洞了
Sammy, I think we found the bat cave.
早啊
Morning.
记录者淋浴室的水压可真好啊
The, uh, water pressure in the letters' shower room is marvelous.
但我还是不明白怎么可能会有水
Yeah. I still can't figure out how we even have water...
或是电力
Or electricity.
我就当是还没坏掉了
Yep, well, I am putting that under the "Ain't broke" Column.
听我说  弟弟
Listen, little brother,
别被整懵了  好吗
let's not go all geek on this stuff, okay?
整懵了
"Geek"?
嗯
Yeah.
别误会
Yeah, I mean, don't -- don't get me wrong.
这些东西太棒了
This stuff is awesome,
看来他们这里的装备不错
And it looks like they ran a real tight outfit here,
我就是说  别...
But I'm just saying, you know, don't, uh,
别觉得好像他们知道什么我们不知道的
don't think that they knew some big secrets that we don't know.
迪恩
Dean...
他们是秘密社团
They were a secret society.
也就是说他们胡编乱造
Which means that they made crap up
戴着毡帽腰带  到处挥舞短刀
and wore fezzes and sashes and swung around scimitars.
大概都没开刃呢
They probably didn't even sharp--
挺锋利的
That's very sharp.
迪恩  听我说
Dean, look,
我觉得这些东西可能有价值
I think we might have something here --
能够帮助我们  帮助人类
something that could help us, help humanity.
至少亨利是这么认为的
Henry certainly thought so.
你也知道  我们很需要走一回运了
I mean, you know damn well we could use a break.
或许这就是撞大运了呢
What if we finally got one?
你要不要把死人的浴袍脱下来
Are you gonna take off the dead-guy robe?
宾夕法尼亚  威尔基斯-巴尔
都这个点了
It's so late.
没想到你会来呢
I didn't expect you in at all.
我今天要换三次车才甩掉他
Three times I had to transfer the bus lines to lose him today.
是啊  那个大坏蛋
Right -- your sinister friend.
你不相信我被人跟踪了
You don't believe me I'm being followed.
反正谁都不信
Nobody ever does.
我要看FD113号手稿
So, yes, I would like to see, uh, manuscript fd113
在霍辛格宅邸找到的
from the Holtzinger estate.
天呐
Oh, my.
你要把所有手稿都整理一遍吗
You're going to catalogue that whole collection for us, aren't you?
如果有这必要的话
If I have to.
谢谢
Thank you.
找到了
Gottenyu.
这本书  我们得保护好它
This book -- we need to protect it.
那个跟着我的东西  他太接近了
This thing they put on me -- he's too close!
我不能随身带着它
I can't take this ledger with me!
当然不能
Of course you can't.
这是特殊参考书区的藏书
It's part of the special reference section,
放在那儿会很安全
where it will be perfectly safe.
我还有十分钟  对吧
I still have 10 minutes, yes?
八分钟
Eight minutes...
到时所有书刊就得归还至前台了
Before all materials must be returned to the main desk.
希望他们给的工钱不错
值得你做这么个讨厌鬼
校园酒吧
请在嘟声后留言
Please leave a message at the tone.
听我说
Now, listen to me carefully.
我没时间了
I got no time left.
我找到了  找到了
I found it! I found it!
等你找到我这儿来
When you -- when you follow me here,
你会需要这个号码
you're gonna need this number here --
Q
Q...
别害羞啊  进来
Why so shy? Come in!
别待在冷风里
Come in out of the cold!
来跟你的老对手喝杯咖啡
You'll have a cup of coffee with -- with your old enemy.
你个纳粹垃圾
You Nazi piece of rubbish!
你个纳粹猪猡
You nazi pig!
两周后
凯文怎么样了
So... how's Kevin doing?
就那样  没什么事
You know. He's okay, I guess.
就在那儿自顾自地解达・芬奇密码呢
In his corner, hacking out his "Da vinci code""
还没什么进展
Nothing actionable yet.
盖思让我代好
Garth says hi, by the way.
小卡有消息吗
Anything from Cass?
完全没有  怎么  你呢
No. Not -- not a peep. Why? You?
没有  他不回应我
No, he's, uh -- he's not answering.
好吧
Right.
我在试着标记出
Well, uh, so I have been trying to chart out
记录者的猎人网络  他们的盟友
the letters' network of hunters, their allies,
还有他们与之合作的和做了记录的附属团体
uh, affiliated groups they worked with, kept files on.
1958年前后的吗
Circa 1958?
没错
Yeah. True.
大部分都已经死去或不存在了
Uh, most are dead or defunct,
但其他的不清楚
but others -- I'm not so sure,
但这个
And this one...
你得看看
...you should definitely check out.
犹大计划吗
The Judah initiative?
欧洲团体
European team --
他们在二战期间有行动
They were active during world war ii.
真的  猎人还参战  挺牛的啊
Really? Hunters fighting in a war -- that's cool.
不完全是猎人  也不算是参战
Not exactly hunters, n-n-not exactly fighting,
-而是...  -拉比啊
- but, uh... - Rabbis.
拉比啊
Rabbis?
真的假的
Really?
记录者对他们的记录很概括
The letters' file on them is sketchy,
但显然他们是中坚破坏分子
But, apparently, they were hard-core saboteurs.
所以我查了这个计划的所有成员
So, I ran a search on the initiative's entire roster,
查到一个  一个拉比艾萨克・巴斯
and I got a hit -- one rabbi Isaac Bass.
加入计划是只有17岁
He was 17 years old when he joined the initiative
去世时85岁
and 85 years old when he died...
那是半个月前
Two weeks ago.
在东部的一个大学城  被烧成焦炭
In a college town back east, he was capped.
焦炭
"Capped"?
没错
Yeah.
他去那儿做调查
He was there doing research,
根据目击者叙述  他自燃了
and according to eyewitnesses, he spontaneously combusted.
那么
So...
这就是活儿了
This is a case?
这才刚回家
I just got back.
你跟已故的巴斯拉比是同事吗
So you...worked with the late rabbi Bass?
我是巴斯拉比的研究助理
I was a research associate of rabbi Bass, yes.
我想帮他完成最后的论文并发表
I'm trying to complete his last paper for publication.
我想看看他是来这儿找什么的
I'd just like to review what he was after here.
那可不少呢
Well, that would be quite a lot of material.
他几乎有一周时间都整天泡在这儿
He was here open to close for almost a week.
那么那些他...
Um, how about just the stuff he was looking at...
就是...
you know, the day he, uh...
去世当日看的呢
caught fire?
那可少多了
Does shorten the list a bit.
他真是个和蔼的怪老头
He was a really nice old kook,
真的很亲切
Really nice.
怪  怎么说
Kook? How so?
他话特别多
You know, he'd talk a lot
跟我们说  自言自语  跟任何愿意听的人说
to us, to himself, to anyone who'd listen.
他总是说有什么秘密的战争
He was always talking about this secret war
没人知道的战争
that nobody knew was going on.
就是阴谋论  他对纳粹很痴迷
Conspiracy stuff -- he was obsessed with nazis.
但他说那些人是"特别的纳粹"
But he said they were "Special nazis," you know...
就是巫师
necromancers.
巫师
necromancers?
就是我弟弟常玩的那个
Yeah, like from that world of whatever-craft
《魔兽世界》里的那种
that my little brother is always playing.
纳粹...巫师
Nazi...necromancers.
真是可悲啊
It's sad, isn't it --
老人都会这样变得疯狂
That old people have to go so crazy?
是啊  真可悲
I know. It is sad.
你们...
You, um...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你们都目睹了意外吗
You, uh, you both saw the accident?
我还能听见他的尖叫
I can still hear his screams.
那火焰就像是活的
It was like the fire was alive,
就像是在攻击他
Like -- like it was attacking him.
就像看一部可怕的电影
It was like watching the most awful movie
真是最可怕最恐怖的一幕了
of the most terrible thing you could possibly see.
没错  就是这样
It was like that.
是啊
Yeah.
北美鸟类探密指南
伯兰特工
Special agent Bolann.
是嘛
Oh, really?
我以为你是猎头什么的呢
I thought you were like a headhunter or something.
我今天碰到你两三次了
This is the second, maybe third time I'm seeing you today?
你跟着我干什么
Why you following me, gingerbread?
我们
Oh, so we um...
我们刚刚没有那个吗
...we didn't have a thing back there, huh?
你说什么
Back where? W-what, now?
真抱歉  我以为
I'm sorry, man. I-I thought
我以为刚刚在院子里我们...
I thought we had a thing back at the quad, you know --
看对眼了呢
a little "eye magic" moment,
我看到你在这儿
And I saw you here
就想着等你办完公事
and I figured I'd wait until you were done with your meeting
或许我们能
and then maybe we might, uh...
好吧  不是那样的
Yeah. Uh, okay, but no --
没什么看对眼
Uh, no moment.
这是联邦调查
This is a... federal investigation.
你这样不是更有意思了吗
Is that supposed to make you less interesting?
不不  抱歉
No. I-I'm sorry, man.
希望没吓到你什么的
I hope -- I hope I didn't freak you out or anything.
不不  没吓到
No. No. I-I'm n-not freaked out.
就是这套打扮闹的
It's just a, you know... A federal thing.
就是...
It's, uh...
好的  老百姓
Okay, citizen.
你继续吧
As you were.
祝你晚安
You have a good night.
你...
You -- you...
你也...好吧
...have a -- okay.
说
Yeah.
我看了一下拉比的调研
So I, uh, looked into the rabbi's research.
但没怎么弄明白
It doesn't make a lot of sense --
是关于鸟类观察的
...Bird watching.
这边两位火辣的
Well, uh, the two very hot co-captains
女子排球队队长
of the women's volleyball team
一致认为拉比的死很不寻常
agree that the rabbi's death was very unnatural.
不论如何还是有蹊跷
I think we still got a case.
怪不得我鞋子上沾了东西呢
That would explain why I have something stuck to my shoe.
有人跟踪你
You being followed?
-好像是的  -真是奇怪
- Yeah, I think so. - That's weird.
我之前也以为自己被跟踪了
I thought I was being followed earlier.
结果是被男人看上了
Turned out to be a gay thing.
什么
What?
没事  要我帮忙吗
Nothing. You need a hand?
好啊
Yes, please.
有隐蔽的地方吗
Got someplace quiet?
郊区访客停车场
Visitors parking -- the boonies.
我半小时后停在后面
I'll park in the back. 30 minutes.
伙计
Hey, pal.
迪恩
Dean?
住手
Stop.
我的脾啊
Oh, my spleen.
那是什么鬼东西
What...the hell...is that?
他是泥人
He's a golem.
他是我的泥人
Well, he's my golem.
好吧
Right.
那个被杀的拉比  艾萨克・巴斯
The rabbi who was murdered, Isaac Bass,
他是我爷爷  我们为此而来
he was my grandfather. That's why we're here.
你们开始调查这个案子
When you guys started to follow up on his case,
我们就开始跟踪你们
we started following you.
等等
So, wait.
那么我们俩
What you're saying is that you and me --
没有看对眼喽
We, uh, didn't have a moment?
没有  我是在跟踪你
No, man. I was tailing you.
就说有人跟踪我
Told you I was being followed.
我说的男人就是他
He was my gay thing.
挺不错啊  真把我骗住了
That was really good. You really had me there.
真会瞎编
That's very smooth.
是啊  我也就这点本事了
Yeah, well, smooth is just about all I got.
怎么了
What?
是啊  继续溜达吧
Yeah, that's right. Keep walking...
你个小家伙
...you chia pet.
那是个泥人
So, that's a golem?
是的
Yes...
粘土造型  拉比给他们生命
Shaped from clay and brought to life by rabbis
以保护犹太人度过
to protect the jewish people in times of --
怎么说呢  各种倒霉事吧
I don't know -- general crappiness.
他是你的
And he's yours?
算不上吧
Hardly.
是我爷爷留给我的
My grandfather left him to me.
他是最后一位活着的成员后裔
I'm the last surviving descendant of the members of this...
是个什么计划
thing, this...initiative.
-犹大计划  -没错
- The judah initiative? - Right, and he --
谁
Who?!
他们怎么知道犹大计划
Who are they to know about the men of judah?
没事的
It's okay.
我们可是好人
We are the good guys.
是的
Yeah.
我们是猎人  萨姆和迪恩・温彻斯特
W-we're hunters, uh -- Sam and Dean Winchester.
我们知道犹大计划
We know about the judah initiative
因为我们的爷爷是记录者
because our grandfather was a man of letters.
嗯
Yes.
拉比知道记录者
The rabbis knew the men of letters.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thanks.
请坐
Take a seat.
那  你们爷爷
So... your grandfather
也喜欢这些超自然的东西吗
was into all this supernatural stuff, too?
爷爷  外公外婆  老爸老妈  一堆亲戚
Yeah, grandparents, mom, dad, truckload of cousins --
一家人都干这个
The whole family was lousy for it,
但我们可没有泥人
But we... never had a golem.
是啊  这些事伴我们长大
Right. Yeah. We, um, we grew up in it,
你不是吗
But you...didn't?
我爷爷的冒险
My grandfather's adventures,
计划  泥人  还有战争
the initiative, the golem, the war --
都是我小时候他讲给我听的故事
They were the stories that he told me when I was a kid.
我以为都是假的呢
I thought it was make-believe.
我父母也是
So did my parents --
就是一些幻想
You know, fantasies
他面对自己目睹的可怕的事的办法
to help him cope with all the horrible stuff he'd seen,
但时不时的  疯爷爷巴斯
But every once in a while, crazy old grandpa Bass
会旅行回来
would come back by on one of his trips,
给我20块的储蓄公债
hand me a $20 savings bond,
说有一天你会继承衣钵
and say, "One day, you'll inherit the mantle."
他死后几天  果然
Sure enough, a few days after he died,
我公寓收到个大盒子
this big box shows up at my apartment.
他总说我会知道怎么做
He always said I'd know what to do
净瞎说
which is crap.
因为我一开箱子
Because when I opened that box,
这个裸体的丑八怪加疯子
this big, naked, potato-faced lunatic
突然醒来发疯了
wakes up and goes crazy!
我没有
I didn't...go crazy.
你把我的娱乐中心都毁了
You trashed my entertainment center!
我的水床
And my water bed.
这个男孩什么都不知道  不遵守戒律
This boy knows nothing, observes none of the mitzvahs,
安息日还工作  吃猪肉
labors on sabbath, dines on swine.
谁不喜欢培根啊
Everybody loves bacon!
他跟拉比不能比
He's no rabbi.
[希伯来语]
Yifalchunbee!
别又提那些了
Don't start with that stuff again.
[希伯来语]
Yifalchunbee!
够了  拜托
Enough! Please!
闭嘴
Quiet time!
什么情况  他在说什么
All right. What was that? What was he saying?
是希伯来语的"接管"
It's Hebrew for something like "take charge",
但我完全不知道什么意思
but I have no idea what he means.
我在肖特山长大[新泽西州]
Look, I grew up in Short Hills.
我希伯莱语学校是靠作弊毕业的
I cheated my way through Hebrew school.
我从没好好倾听过我祖父
I never really listened to my grandfather,
倾听他说的话
what he was saying.
等等  他就送了你  这个泥人
So, wait -- he just sends you this -- this Golem
然后指望你自己想明白吗
and expects you to work it out?
他没什么机会培养我
He didn't get much chance to prepare me, I guess.
我父母
My parents --
他们尽其所能
they did everything they could to prevent him
不让他那些疯言疯语毁了我
from screwing me up with all his crazy talk.
战后
See, after the war,
我祖父穷其一生
my grandfather spent the rest of his life
去追踪一个什么修黎社
trying to track down something he called the Thule Society.
修黎社  都是纳粹
The Thule Society. Right. They were nazis.
纳粹巫师
Nazi necromancers.
巫  什么
N-necro-who?
巫师  就是女巫  魔法师
Uh, necromancer-- uh, witches, sorcerers,
黑魔法  大多是用在死人身上的
dark magic, mostly with dead people.
好吧
Okay.
关于修黎社  我只知道
All I know about the Thule
他们是个极扭曲秘密的社团
is that they were this twisted, secret fraternity,
想一统世界
Hell-bent on world domination,
资助过早期纳粹党
that sponsored the early days of the nazi party.
我祖父说
My grandfather said
犹大计划就是为与之抗衡
the Judah Initiative was started to fight them.
修黎社杀害了你祖父  小朋友
And the Thule murdered your grandfather, boy.
快找到他们  好让我干活
Find them so I can do my work!
这地方是租的
We're renting here!
租的
Renting.
我觉得我的泥人说的对
I think my golem's right.
我爷爷
My grandfather...
他临死那天在我的机器上留言
He left me this message on my machine the day he died,
说他找到了一些
and he said that he had found something
修黎社会为之杀人的东西
that the Thule were willing to kill him for.
他说他把它藏在了显眼的地方
He said he was hiding it here in plain sight.
他留给我了张奇怪的...
He left me this weird...
方程式还是什么的...
I don't know...equation.
不是电话号码  也不是地址或坐标
It's not a phone number or an address or coordinates.
QL673W38
Q-l-6-7-3-w-3-8?
是密码吗
Is it a combination?
是图书编目号码
Oh, it's a call number.
国会图书馆  他们的文件编排系统
Library of congress...their filing system.
大学图书馆都用这个
They use it in college libraries.
QL673是
Uh, q-l-6-7-3...that...
是科学书籍
that's sciences.
我猜是鸟类书籍
Birds, I'm guessing.
我们走
Let's go.
你们随便到哪都擅自闯进去吗
What, do you two just break in wherever you go?
我们老爸想让我们
Yeah, well, our dad wanted us
有一份可以依靠的职业
to have a solid career to fall back on,
以防猎人生涯不顺
Just in case this hunter thing didn't pan out.
如果我没想错的话  我觉得你爷爷
Okay, so if I'm right, then I think your grandfather
把FD113手稿从档案馆里换了出来
switched manuscript FD113 out of the archives.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
我欠你个人情
I owe you thanks.
拉比把我领到这儿
The rabbi got me this far,
但是你  让我找到了它
But you... took me all the way.
把记录薄给我
Now, give me the ledger.
救命
Help!
巫师
N-necromancer!
待在这
Stay here!
见鬼
Crap.
Crap!
喂  大个子
Hey, big guy,
如果我们不抓住施咒者  他们都会死
they're both gonna die unless we get whoever cast the spell.
起来  起来
Come on. Come on.
修黎社
Long live...
万岁
The thule.
或者死翘翘
Or not.
噢  哎呀
Oh...man.
是记录者治好了你
The men of letters healed you.
他们救了你的命
They saved your life.
他们在干啥
What are they doing?
埋掉巫师
Burying the necromancer.
真像一袋子乐高玩具
That's like a bag of legos.
泥人解决了这家伙
The golem destroyed this guy.
是啊
Yeah.
那么  修黎社巫师搞定了
So, uh...thule society necromancers aside,
我们怎么对付那边的家伙
what's our contingency plan on that?
你是说我们怎样对那边的杀手比尔喊"饶命"
You mean how do we "Oh, no!" Mr. Bill over there?
有必要的话当然可以这样
I mean, I'd like to think we could if we had to.
除非你以为亚伦可以控制他
Unless you think Aaron can get a handle on him.
天啊  他们疯了
Oh, my god. These guys are psychopaths.
你查到了什么
What'd you find out?
我认为那是白俄罗斯纳粹军营里的一本记录簿
I think it's a log-book from a nazi compound in Belarus.
由修黎社管理
It was run by the thule.
是红记录簿
This is the red ledger.
在军营毁于大火时就不见了
It was lost in the fire that destroyed the compound,
但我祖父相信战后就有人找到了
but my grandfather was convinced it had been found after the war.
里面记述了针对军营里的人
Well, it describes the horrible experiments
所进行的可怕实验
performed on the camp's population...
魔法实验
Magical experiments.
难以形容的可怕
More horrible than words.
你当时在场  对吧
You were there, weren't you?
在军营里
At the camp?
我是在维台普斯克犹太居住区制造出来的
I was made in the ghetto of Vitsyebsk
就是为了摧毁那个地方
to tear that hell down.
我破墙而入  见人就杀
I broke its walls, its men.
指挥官把我所在的地方烧成了灰
The commandant burnt the place to ash around me.
好吧  那你说
Okay, um, w-what does it mean
让亚伦下令是什么意思
when -- when you tell Aaron to take charge?
那小子如果查了资料  他就会知道
The boy would know... if he could consult the pages.
资料  什么资料
Pages? W-what pages?
在我...在我行受戒礼的时候
When I was -- when I was bar mitzvahed,
我祖父给了我一本薄薄的旧书
my -- my grandfather gave me this little old book.
是希伯来语写的
It was in hebrew.
算是泥人的使用手册
It was like an owner's manual for a golem.
很好  那就学啊
Okay. Great. Get that, then.
可我没能...
I I can't...exactly.
我上了中学  有点玩世不恭
When I went to high school, I sort of...drifted.
我没心思学习
I started getting off the academic track,
于是我就...
and, uh, I kind of...
就卷起来点了
...I kind of smoked it.
小子用书页卷了烟
The boy smoked the pages.
那纸张只有这么薄  牛皮纸
They were these thin, vellum-y pages.
卷烟是再合适不过了
I-I mean, it was perfect for rolling.
听着  几张破纸就能操纵泥巴人
Look, they were driving instructions for a clay man.
这不是荒唐吗
Okay? It was nonsense.
好吗  我是说
Right? I mean...
我...
I...
好吧  我很抱歉  行了吧
Okay. All right. Look, I'm sorry, okay?
有什么需要我学的  你告诉我不就行了
Why can't you just tell me what I don't know?!
我没有资格指导拉比
It's not my place to guide the rabbi,
教授教师
to teach the teacher!
这不是我的责任
It's not my place!
接管
Yifalchunbee!
这个  确实让人不怎么舒服
That's not super-comforting, got to say.
我只能说  那些实验
So as far as I can tell, these experiments --
修黎社残杀犹太人  吉普赛人
the thule were murdering Jews, Gypsies --
基本上没人能幸免
Just about anybody and everybody --
然后用魔法使他们复活
then trying to magically reanimate them.
他们企图找到方法
They were trying to figure out a way
让死去的自己人复活
to bring their own dead back to life...
我估计他们最后成功了
Which I'm guessing they figured out
因为这个
because -- this.
最后一页
This last page...
所有死而复生的修黎社人的名册
Is a roster of every dead thule member who was reanimated.
他们就因此杀了我祖父
This is why they killed my grandfather?
上面写了怎么干掉他们吗
Anything in there on how to kill it?
很明显他们做了这样的实验
Apparently, they experimented with that, too.
爆头
Headshot...
但如果十二个小时内没有烧掉尸体
But if you don't burn the body within 12 hours,
就会复活
it reanimates again.
混账纳粹
Nazi bastards.
摄像头记录全部被销毁了
The security camera's hard drives have all been wiped.
你确定他被干掉了吗
Are you sure he's been murdered?
托瓦兹死在这里
Torvald was killed here,
但杀手不是人类
but not by a man.
我本可以知道更多  可他的魂魄没来得及说
I'd know more, but his ghost was forced to depart
就被迫离开了
before it could tell me.
他们清楚要烧掉尸体
They knew enough to burn his remains.
是血吗
Blood?
泥土
Clay.
托瓦兹杀死了计划的最后一个拉比
Torvald kills the initiative's last rabbi,
如今维台普斯克的泥人杀死了他
and now the golem of Vitsyebsk kills him.
不  盖思  不是工具社会
No, no, Garth, not a tool society --
是修黎社
"Thule" -- t-h-u-l-e.
对
Yeah.
好  有发现就联系我
All right. Call me if you find anything.
盖思的所有线人都没辙
All of Garth's contacts are stumped.
根本就没人听说过
Nobody on the circuit's ever even heard
"修黎社"
of "The Thule Society"
无论是些什么人
Whoever these people are,
他们藏得够深
they've been flying beneath the hunter radar.
有发现吗
Anything?
没什么靠谱的
Nothing solid.
相关的传说倒是不少
I mean, the lore is all over the place.
有个说法是  只要擦去其前额的一个字母
Uh, according to one legend, um, it can be shut down
就可以让其停止行动
if you erase one of the letters off its forehead.
-那张泥巴脸上没有字母  -的确没有
- I didn't see any letters on clayface. - Exactly.
不管这个  另一个是说
So, side-burner that. Another one --
古代传说  泥人
"有的嘴里有卷轴  你要拔出来"
"Some have a scroll in their mouth you're supposed to rip out."
咬着卷轴还能说清楚话吗
Wouldn't that give him some sort of a lisp or something?
根据传说  它们根本就不能说话
Well, classically, they're not even supposed to speak.
我们都知道  他单枪匹马
We do know that he took on an entire camp
解决了全副武装的德军营地
full of heavily armed german soldiers
和修黎社巫师
and thule necromancers and won.
虎头虎脑的大坏蛋
One badass hummel figurine.
我们完全不知道怎么让它熄火
That we have no idea how to put back in the box.
好极了
Great.
这就是你们的计划
So, that's your plan --
解决我的泥人
taking out my Golem?
还不是什么计划
It's not a plan.
只是知道了怎么办  感觉好些  就这样
We would just feel a lot better if we knew how. That's all.
你们凭什么以为自己有权做这样的决定
What makes you think you have any right to make that decision?
相信我
Believe me,
如果我们需要  我们就去争取
if we need the right, we will take it.
听着  他也许很讨人厌
Look, he may be a pain in the ass,
但我要对他负责
but he's my responsibility.
泥人为了战争而创造出来的
Look, the Golem was built to go to war.
你可没受到这样的训练
You're not trained for that.
你打算如何继续下去
Now, how are you gonna take that on?
我不知道
I don't know.
住手
Enough!
找到你了  残酷无情的怪物
There you are, you grim piece of work,
找你好多年了
after all these years.
艾克哈特
Eckhart.
亚当之泥  向我投降
我以创造者所订立的契约命令你
I command you by the covenant of your makers --
亚当之泥  向我投降
Clay of Adam, surrender your bond unto me.
你是泥人的拉比
So, you are the golem's rabbi?
你唤醒了他
You woke him...
却没有占有他
...but you didn't take possession of him.
要把名字写在卷轴上
You write your name on the scroll, boy.
这样你才能  接管他
That's how you... yifalchunbee.
我不知道他是什么意思
I didn't know what he meant.
知识就是力量  是不是
Knowledge is power, isn't it?
你们谁来告诉我
Now, which of you is going to tell me
我在哪能找到红记录薄
where I can find a certain red ledger?
去死吧  纳粹猪
How about you screw yourself, nazi bastard?
我们
Can we...
我们能不能把纳粹的问题放一边
Could we put the nazi thing aside for the moment
好好说话  就像对
and just talk about this like --
纳粹巫师混蛋吗  算了吧
Nazi necromancer dicks? Pass.
你就是指挥官吧
So I take it you're the commandant?
批准所有试验的人
The one that authorized all those experiments?
发明了
Invented...
那些试验  谢谢
those experiments. Thank you.
你呢
So, what about you?
你不是
I mean, you're not...
不死之人
Undead.
你做了什么
So what did you do?
给自己施了个永葆青春的咒语吗
You cast a "forever 21" spell on yourself,
就像图书馆你那位朋友那样
Like your little friend at the library?
他叫托瓦兹
His name was Torvald.
你会为此付出代价的
And you will suffer for that.
我得说  不管有没有施咒
You know, I got to say, spell or no spell,
他挺弱不禁风的
he broke easy,
看来
so...
抱歉  那么
I'm sorry. "So.."
还是我说说吧
Let me tell you what I see.
我脚边就有个魔法犹太人  却没有主人
A magic jew at my feet, not a master in sight,
而且  我们的秘密终于又保住了
and, finally, our secrets secret once again.
让我想到了一个故事
Which reminds me of a story.
一个犹太人  两个非犹太人和一个泥人进酒吧
"A jew, two gentiles, and a golem walk into a bar""
而他们没都出去
And it doesn't end with them coming out.
傻瓜
Fools!
你可以杀我
You can kill me.
但你们杀不尽修黎社
But you will never kill all the Thule.
至少是个开始
Well, that's a start.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
现在我们知道
Well, now we know --
纸能制服泥人
Paper beats golem,
火能制服不死的纳粹僵尸
Fire beats undead nazi zombie freaks.
那么
So...
怎么样  亚伦
What do you say, Aaron?
我们有个地方可以存放他
I mean, we got a place we can keep him.
不
No.
毕竟
I mean...
艾克哈特虽然死了  但你也听到了
Eckhart might be dead, but you heard him.
还是有修黎社的
The Thule are still out there...
偷偷地行动着
Hidden, active.
那是我爷爷
That's my grandfather.
他给我留下了重要的东西
He left me something important.
只有我能做的事
Something only I can do.
看来我也是犹大计划的人了
It looks like I'm the judah initiative now.
接管
Yifalchunbee.
我不是已经做了吗
B-but I thought I did.
是的
Yes.
你干什么呢
What're you doing?
排号
Ordering --
我在做项目卡
I'm making a card entry for our, uh,
给修黎社的红记录薄的副本做的
copies from the Thule's red ledger for our collection.
怎么
So, uh, what?
亚伦加入了犹大计划
Aaron's a J.I., and...
你也成了记录者了吗
You're a man of letters now? Is that it?
好啊
Good.